So, I ran all the cells in my notebook and here's
我运行了 notebook 中的所有单元格
my solution and definition for the SkipGramNeg Module.
下面说说我是如何定义 SkipGramNeg 模型的
First, I've defined my two embedding layers, in-embed and out-embed,
首先定义 in-embed 和 out-embed 这两个嵌入层
and they'll both take in the size of
它们的参数都包括词汇表大小
our word vocabulary and produce embeddings of size and embed.
并生成大小为 n_embed 的嵌入
So, mapping from our vocab to our embedding dimension.
从而将词汇表映射到嵌入维度
Here, I'm doing an additional step which is initializing
在这里用范围为 -1 到 1 的均匀权重
the embedding look-up tables with uniform weights between negative one and one.
初始化嵌入查询表
I'm doing this for both of our layers and I believe
我对这两个层级都执行了这一步
this helps our model reached the best way faster.
这样可以帮助模型更快地达到最佳状态
Then I've defined my three forward functions.
然后定义三个 forward 函数
Forward input passes our input words through our input
forward_input 将输入字词传入输入嵌入层
embedding layer and returns input embedding vectors.
并返回输入嵌入向量
I do the same thing in forward output only passing that
forward_output 也差不多
through our output embedding layer to get output vectors.
不过传入的是输出嵌入层 并获得输出向量
Notice that there are no linear layers or softmax activation functions here.
注意这里没有线性层级或 softmax 激活函数
The last forward function is forward noise,
最后一个 forward 函数是 forward_noise
which will return a noisy target embeddings.
它将返回一个噪点目标嵌入
So, this samples noisy words from our noise distribution and
这些噪点样本字词来自噪点分布
returns the number of samples batch size times N samples.
返回 (batch_size * n_samples) 个样本
Then we get the embeddings bypassing
然后将这些噪点字词传入输出嵌入层
those noise words through our output embedding layer.
来获得嵌入
In the same line,
在同一行
I'm reshaping these to be the size I want,
将这些向量变形为我想要的大小
which is batch size by N samples by our embedding dimension and I return those vectors.
即 (batch_size, n_samples, n_embed) 然后返回这些向量
Okay, so this completes the SkipGramNeg Module.
这就是完整的 SkipGramNeg 模型
Next, I'm defining a custom negative sampling loss.
接下来定义自定义负采样损失
This was carefully defined above in our equations and I
我根据公式定义了该损失函数
haven't ever gotten into the details of defining a custom loss,
虽然之前没有详细讲解如何定义自定义损失
but suffice to say that it is really similar to defining a model class.
但是不用担心 它和定义 model 类很像
Only in this case, the init function is left
只不过 init 函数留空了
empty and we're really left with defining the forward function.
只需定义 forward 函数
The forward function should take in some inputs and targets
forward 函数会接受输入和目标参数
typically and you can define what it takes in as parameters here.
我们可以在这里定义一些其他参数
This should return a single value that indicates the average loss over a batch of data.
它应该返回一个值 表示一批数据的平均损失
So, in this case, I know I what my loss to look at an input embedded vector,
负采样损失需要查看输入嵌入向量、
my correct output embedding,
正确输出嵌入向量
and my incorrect noisy vectors.
以及错误噪点向量
So here, I am getting the batch size and
在这里根据输入向量的形状
embedding dimension from the shape of my input vector,
获取批次大小和嵌入维度
then I'm shaping my input vector into a shape that is batch first,
然后将输入向量变形为 batch_first 的形状
and I'm doing something similar to my output vector here,
在这里变形输出向量
only I'm swapping these last two dimensions
将维度 embed_size 和 1 调换过来
one an embed size effectively making this the output vector transpose.
变成输出向量转置矩阵
This way, I'll be able to calculate the.product between
这样便能够对这两个向量执行批量矩阵乘法运算
these two vectors by performing batch matrix multiplication on them,
从而计算这两个向量的点积
and that's just what I'm doing here.
也就是这一步的作用
First, I'm calculating the loss term between
首先计算输入向量
my input vector and my correct target vector.
与正确目标向量之间的损失项
I'm using batch matrix multiplication and then applying a sigmoid and a log function.
在这里采用批量矩阵乘法运算 (bmm) 然后应用 S 型函数和对数函数
Here, I'm squeezing the output so that no empty dimensions are left in the output.
在这里对输出运行 squeeze() 使输出中没有任何空的维度
Next, I'm doing something similar only between
接下来对输入向量与否定的噪点向量
my input vector and my negated noise vectors.
执行相似的步骤
So, this is the second term in our loss function.
这是损失函数的第二项
I'm using batch matrix multiplication,
在这里执行批量矩阵乘法运算
applying a sigmoid and a log function,
并应用 S 型函数和对数函数
and then I'm summing the losses over the sample of noise vectors.
然后对噪点向量样本的损失求和
Okay finally, I'm adding these two losses up negating them since I kept them
最后将这两个损失加起来并取负数
positive during my calculations and taking the mean of this total loss.
因为我在计算过程中求得是正值 然后对总损失求平均值
This way, I'm returning the average negative sample loss over a batch of data.
这样就能返回一批数据的平均负采样损失
Then I can move on to creating this model and training it.
继续创建并训练该模型
This training loop will look pretty similar to before,
这个训练循环和之前的很像
but with some key differences.
不过也有一些显著差别
First, I'm creating a unigram noise distribution that
首先 在这里创建均匀噪点分布
relates noisy vectors to their frequency of occurrence,
将噪点向量与出现频率关联起来
and this is a value I calculated earlier in this notebook.
我之前计算了这个值
So, I'm defining our noise distribution as
将噪点分布定义为均匀分布
the unigram distribution raised to a power
并根据论文中的说明
of three-fourths as was specified in the paper.
将幂数设为 0.75
Then, I'm defining my model passing in the length of
然后在这里定义模型 传入词汇表长度
our vocabulary and embedding dimension which I left as 300,
并将嵌入维度设为 300
and this noise distribution that I've just created,
并传入这个刚刚创建的噪点分布
and I'm moving this altered GPU.
将数据全部移到 GPU 上
Then I have another key difference,
另一个重要区别是
instead of using NLL loss,
我没有使用 NLLloss
I'm using my custom negative sampling loss that I defined above.
而是使用在上面定义的自定义负采样损失
In my training loop, I'll have to pass in three parameters to this loss function.
在训练循环里 需要向这个损失函数传入三个参数
So, I'm training for five epochs again,
训练 5 个周期
getting batches of input and target words.
在这里获取批量输入和目标字词
Then using my three different forward functions I'm getting my input embedding,
然后使用三个不同的 forward 函数
my desired output embedding,
获取输入嵌入向量、输出嵌入向量
and my noise embeddings.
和噪点嵌入向量
So, forward input takes in my inputs,
向 forward_input 中传入 inputs
forward output takes in my targets and forward noise takes in two parameters.
向 forward_output 中传入 targets
It takes in a batch size and a number of noise vectors to generate.
forward_noise 有两个参数 一个是批次大小 另一个是要生成的噪点向量数量
Then to calculate my loss,
然后计算损失
I'm passing in my input,
在这里传入输入向量、
output and noise embeddings here.
输出向量和噪点向量
Then, I just have the same code as before,
这些是和之前一样的代码
performing backpropagation and optimization steps as usual,
执行反向传播和优化步骤
and I have my validation similarities that I'm going to print
在这里输出验证相似性
out along with the epoch and loss, a little more information.
以及周期和损失
So, note that I chose to define my three different forward functions
我定义了三个不同的 forward 函数
just so I a get the vectors that I needed to calculate my negative sampling loss here.
目的是获得计算负采样损失所需的向量
You can try training this yourself just to see how much faster this training is.
你可以自己试试训练该模型 看看训练速度提高了多少
Then imprinting data less frequently because it's generated quicker.
我输出数据的频率低了 因为数据生成速度更快
So here, after the first epoch,
在第 1 个周期之后
we see our usual sort of noisy relationships.
字词之间的关系不太紧密
But by the end of training,
但是在训练完毕后
we see words grouped together that makes sense.
字词分组变得更加合理了
So, we have mathematics, algebra,
例如 mathematics algebra,
calculus, we have ocean,
calculus 是一组
islands, Pacific, Atlantic,
ocean islands pacific atlantic 变成了一组
and some smaller words that all seem to be grouped together as well.
一些小词也组合到了一起
Once again, I visualize the word vectors using T-SNE.
使用 T-SNE 可视化字词向量
This time I'm visualizing fewer words and I'm getting
不过可视化的字词数量变少了
the embeddings from our input embedding layer only.
并且仅从输入嵌入层获取嵌入
Then I'm passing these embeddings into our T-SNE model and this is the result I get.
将这些嵌入传入 T-SNE 模型 结果是这样的
I can see some individual integers grouped over here,
这些是整数词
some educational terms and war and military terms over here.
这些是教育术语 这些是战争和军事术语
I see some governmental terms and other relationships
这些是政府术语 还有其他各种词汇
and it's pretty interesting to poke around a visualization like this.
这样的图表看起来比较有意思
The word2vec model always makes me think about
word2vec 模型总是让我觉得
how a learned vector space can be really interesting.
模型生成的向量空间很有趣
Just think about how you might embed images and find relationships between
例如我们可以嵌入图像并发现颜色和对象之间的关系
colors and objects or how you might transform words using vector arithmetic.
例如使用向量运算转换字词
Building and training this model was also quite involved and if you feel comfortable with
这个模型构建和训练起来很复杂
this model code and especially manipulating models to
如果你能熟练编写模型代码
add your own forward functions and custom loss types,
并自己添加 forward 函数和自定义损失类型
you've really learned a lot about the Pythonic nature of PyTorch and model customization.
那么你已经熟练掌握 PyTorch 的 Python 特性和模型自定义方法了
In addition to implementing a very effective word2vec model.
而且能自己构建非常高效的 word2vec 模型
So, great job on making it this far,
做得很好
and I hope you're excited to learn even more.
接下来内容更精彩哦